envoy.com 2003-02-08

# WebMD Professional Portal Privacy Policy and Agreement

#### WebMD Professional Portal Privacy Policy and Agreement

Your privacy is important to WebMD. We want you to feel as comfortable as possible visiting our web site and using its services. This Privacy Policy and Agreement ("Privacy Policy") tells you what information we collect about you and your use of our professional web site. This policy also explains how we protect that information and what choices you have about how it is used. We urge you to read this Privacy Policy carefully so that you will understand clearly both our commitment to you and your privacy, and how we may collect and use information. By using the WebMD professional site, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy.

WebMD is a licensee of the  TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent, nonprofit organization whose goal is to build users' trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. As required of TRUSTe licensees, we will inform you of the following in this privacy policy:

  * What personally identifiable information of yours is collected;
  * What organization is collecting the information;
  * How the information is used;
  * With whom the information may be shared;
  * What choices are available regarding collection, use and distribution of the information;
  * What kind of security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under our control; and,
  * How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information.

We hope that reading our Privacy Policy gives you a clear idea of how we manage information about you. For immediate access to a particular topic, click on the title of that Article.

> **ARTICLE 1.   What This Privacy Policy Covers**
> 
> **ARTICLE 2.   Information We Collect**
>
>> > Registration and Profile  
>  Services and Interactive Areas  
>  Cookies  
>  Children  
>  Public Forums
> 
> **ARTICLE 3.    Disclosure of Your Information**
>
>> > Disclosure to WebMD Subsidiaries  
>  Disclosure in the Context of Mergers and Acquisitions  
>  Disclosure for Credit Card Charges  
>  Disclosure for Marketing Purposes  
>  Disclosure to WebMD Operations and Maintenance Contractors  
>  Disclosure to Transaction Partners  
>  Disclosure to Co-Sponsors of Services  
>  Disclosure in the Context of Linked Web Sites  
>  Disclosure to Other Third Parties  
>  Disclosure of Aggregate Information
> 
> **ARTICLE 4.   How WebMD Handles Privacy Internally**

> **ARTICLE 5.   Your Privacy Choices**

> **ARTICLE 6.   Updating Your Personal Information and Contacting WebMD**

**ARTICLE 1**

**What This Privacy Policy Covers**

This Privacy Policy applies only to the WebMD professional web site ("Site"). Some of the links on our Site connect to other web sites. Once you leave our Site and enter another web site (whether through an advertisement, co-brand, service, or content link), be aware any information you disclose on or through those sites is not subject to this Privacy Policy. WebMD does not endorse and is not responsible for the privacy practices of the third party web sites to which we link. You should always review the privacy policy for those sites to understand how they treat your Personal Information.

Within the Site, this Privacy Policy applies only to the information described below. If you enrolled for any of WebMDs Subscription Services, please review the applicable provisions of the separate Subscriber Agreement, as well as the WebMD Web Site Use Agreement, to understand how we treat the patient information you enter when using those services.

**ARTICLE 2**

** Information We Collect**

_ Registration and Profile_

Personal Information is information that can be used to identify or contact you. You may not use our Site without registering or submitting Personal Information. When you or a representative of your Subscriber register for our Site or any of our services, you or that representative provide information about you and/or your Subscriber. By providing us that information, you consent to our use of that information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If you are enrolled as a member of a Subscriber, whoever completes the enrollment form or registration form (on paper or online) on behalf of your Subscriber represents to us that he/she is authorized by the Subscriber and its personnel to give us consent to use the information included on these forms. We will use that information in accordance with this Privacy Policy unless you, the Subscriber, or the affected individual notifies us to the contrary. We use the Personal Information obtained through registration to respond to questions from you and/or inform you of significant changes to this Privacy Policy. In some cases, we provide this information to third parties. [See ARTICLE 3]. We may also use this information to contact you or send you emails or flash messages with special promotions or with content that we think may be of interest to you or to ask you to participate in a survey.

The information we collect in the enrollment or registration form (on paper or online) and in the Profile ("Registration Information") is listed in the registration section of our site [ [Registration Page]](https://professional.webmd.com/help/mod55/WebMDRegData.htm).

_Services and Interactive Areas_

We also may collect other information, some of which may be Personal Information, that you voluntarily provide to us when you choose to use some of the WebMD Services and Interactive Areas, such as our Practice Site Builder Tool or CME/Prof Education. We also may collect information you provide voluntarily through responses to surveys, questionnaires and the like.

_Cookies_

We may collect anonymous, non-Personal Information about your use of our Site through the use of "cookies". Cookies are small computer files that we transfer to your computer's hard drive that allow us to know how often someone visits our Site and the activities they conduct while on our site (such as the chat rooms visited, etc.). Every computer is assigned a different cookie by WebMD. The information collected by cookies can help us dynamically generate advertising and content on web pages specifically designed for you and also allows us to statistically monitor how many people are using our site and for what purpose. Cookies also help us authenticate our users.

Your browser software can be set to reject all cookies. However, you must at least allow for session-based cookies to use our Site. Most browsers offer instructions on how to reset the browser to reject cookies in the "Help" section of the toolbar.

Sponsors, partners, advertisers, or other third parties on WebMD may also use their own cookies when you click on their advertisement or link to their site or service. Some advertisers use companies other than WebMD to serve their ads and these companies ("Ad Servers") may also collect non-Personal Information through the use of cookies on our Site. We do not control these third parties' use of cookies, or how they manage the non-Personal Information they gather through them. However, we do require Ad Servers to agree that they will not collect any Personal Information from our Site without your consent and to agree they will not link any non-personal cookie information collected by them from our Site to Personal Information they or others collect in other ways or from other sites. You should review the privacy policy of other sites you visit or link to from our Site to understand how these other sites use cookies and how they use the information they collect through the use of cookies on their own sites.

_ Children_

We are committed to protecting the privacy of children. This Site is not designed or intended to attract children under the age of 13. We do not collect Personal Information from any person we actually know is under the age of 13.

_Public Forums_

This Privacy Policy does not protect you when you use any WebMD discussion groups or public forums. As a service to our users, WebMD may feature bulletin boards or online discussions. Any information shared in a bulletin board or online discussion is public information and may be seen or collected by third parties that do not adhere to our Privacy Policy. You should think carefully before disclosing any Personal Information in any public forum.

** ARTICLE 3**

** Disclosure of Your Information**

Except as set forth in this Article or as specifically agreed to by you, WebMD will not disclose any Personal Information it gathers from you on our Site. We may release Personal Information to third parties: (1) to comply with valid legal requirements such as a law, regulation, search warrant, subpoena or court order; or (2) in special cases, such as a physical threat to you or others. In the event that we are legally compelled to disclose your Personal Information to a third party, we will notify you unless doing so would violate the law or court order.

_ Disclosure to WebMD Subsidiaries_

WebMD may disclose Personal Information to its corporate subsidiaries. Any Personal Information provided to subsidiaries of WebMD will be treated by those subsidiaries in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

_ Disclosure in the Context of Mergers and Acquisitions_

WebMD may disclose Personal Information to a company with which it merges, or which acquires WebMD or substantially all of its assets. Any Personal Information provided to such company will be provided subject to that company treating the information in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

_ Disclosure for Credit Card Charges_

To register and pay for certain services on the Site offered by WebMD (in contrast to a service offered by a third party through the Site), e.g., a WebMD-sponsored CME course, you will be asked for credit card information and billing address. This information will be stored in a database on a secure server, and only authorized WebMD employees or contractors will have access to the database. However, WebMD will disclose your credit card and billing information to the financial institutions that process your charges; we may also disclose such information to third parties that provide credit card verification services to us. In accordance with this Privacy Policy, you may contact us to delete credit card information from our systems. We will honor your request, provided that we determine that you do not have an outstanding balance on your account.

_ Disclosure for Marketing Purposes_

WebMD may disclose your Registration Information to its marketing and sales staff and/or to the sales staffs of other companies with which WebMD has joint marketing arrangements, such as practice management companies, for the purpose of contacting you to offer additional services in which we think you may be interested.

_ Disclosure to WebMD Operations and Maintenance Contractors_

WebMD operations and maintenance contractors sometimes have limited access to your Personal Information in the course of providing products or services to WebMD. These contractors include vendors and suppliers that provide us with technology, services, and/or content related to better operation and maintenance of our Site and/or that send emails or letters to you on our behalf or who conducting market research on our behalf. Access to your Personal Information by these contractors is limited to the information reasonably necessary in order for the contractor to perform its limited function for WebMD. We also contractually require that our operations and maintenance contractors 1) protect the privacy of your Personal Information consistent with this Privacy Policy, and 2) not use or disclose your Personal Information for any purpose other than providing us with products and services.

_ Disclosure to Transaction Partners_

WebMDsSubscription Services may allow you to perform certain transactions with health care companies such as labs, payers, PBMs, pharmacies, and hospitals with which you may be affiliated ("Transaction Partners"). WebMD may disclose your Registration Information and information about your use of Subscription Services to the Transaction Partners with which you engage in transactions (and/or their contractors).

_ Disclosure to Co-Sponsors of Services_

If we jointly sponsor a service on our Site with another party, we will share your Personal Information with our co-sponsor to the extent necessary for them to process and provide the service. For instance, WebMD offers Just In Time CME courses in conjunction with various accrediting agencies. If you register for such a course, we will share your Registration Information, but not your credit card information (if any), with those accrediting agencies to enable CME credit tracking.

_ Disclosure in the Context of Linked Web Sites_

WebMD will not disclose your Personal Information to the owners and operators of web sites linked to our Site, except to:

  * _Your Affiliated Organizations_ : The Site may contain co-brands and links to content and services offered by a practice management system, payer, hospital or other organization with which you or your Subscriber is affiliated (e.g., Medical Manager, Medic, Humana). If you have access to the co-branded site and/or such content and services, we may share your Personal Information with your affiliated organizations. For instance, to enable single sign-on from our Site, we may pass your Registration Information onto your affiliated organization when you click on a link to their service.
  * _Web Site Content and Service Providers_ : We allow third parties to offer content and services through the Site by placing links on our Site to their web sites. One example of this is the Cleveland Clinical Internal Medical Review Course, which is hosted and served by Healthstream. Similarly, if you purchase an item through one of WebMDs co-branded stores (e.g., from WebMD Supply Shop), you will be purchasing it from a third party (e.g., medibuy.com). We will not share your Personal Information with these third party content and service providers without your consent, and we will make an effort to make it obvious to you when you leave our Site and enter another web site, either by requiring you to click on a link or by notifying you on the Site.

Please remember that this Privacy Policy no longer applies once you leave our Site and enter a linked third party web site.

_ Disclosure to Other Third Parties_

WebMD may provide your Personal Information to certain third parties with whom we have agreements, including Synergy, Inc., HealthPages and GeoAccess. WebMD also may provide limited Personal Information concerning your utilization of WebMD Subscription Services to third parties, including payers or pharmacy benefit managers ("PBMs"). For example, WebMD may report formulary events to PBMs that monitor formulary compliance. In some cases, WebMD may receive compensation for providing this information.

_ Disclosure of Aggregate Information_

WebMD may provide to third parties non-Personal Information about you that does not allow you to be identified or contacted and that is combined with the non-Personal Information of other users ("Aggregate Information"). For example, we might inform third parties regarding the number of users of our Site and the activities they conduct while on our Site. We might also inform a pharmaceutical company (that may or may not be an advertiser on our Site) that "30% of our users live east of the Mississippi" or that "15% of our users are board certified in Internal Medicine." Depending on the circumstances, we may or may not charge third parties for this Aggregate Information. We also may not limit the third parties use of the Aggregate Information, except that we do require third parties to whom we disclose Aggregate Information to agree that they will not attempt to make this information personally identifiable by combining it with other databases or otherwise.

**ARTICLE 4**

**How WebMD Handles Privacy and Security Internally**

WebMD wants your Personal Information to remain as secure as possible. That is why we have a two-tier security system that combines leading technical safeguards and a code of conduct for those employees that are permitted to access our customers' Personal Information. On the technical side, WebMD uses Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption technology in transmitting your Personal Information to our servers to help ensure the integrity and privacy of the Personal Information you provide to us via the Internet. Encryption involves systematically scrambling numbers and letters, so that even if someone managed to intercept the information, they would not be able to make sense of it. In order to take advantage of this encryption technology, you need to have an Internet browser that will support 128-bit encryption, such as Netscape or Microsoft Explorer. As an additional security measure, your password is encrypted when it is stored on our server. On the employee side, only a limited number of WebMD employees are authorized to access your Personal Information. All WebMD employees must abide by our Privacy Policy and those who violate our Privacy Policy are subject to disciplinary action, up to and including termination. Although we will make every reasonable effort to protect your Personal Information from loss, misuse, or alteration by third parties, you should be aware that there is always some risk involved in transmitting information over the Internet. There is also some risk that thieves could find a way to thwart our security systems.

**ARTICLE 5**

**Your Privacy Choices**

At Registration and at various times as you use the Site, you may have the option of receiving informational/promotional emails or newsletters from WebMD and/or third parties, participating in research or marketing surveys and participating in other activities. You may exercise these options by placing or leaving in place a check mark beside a statement that expresses a preference for receiving these communications or participating in these activities. You may change your decision at any time by changing your preferences within your Profile or by following other directions provided in association with the individual communication or activity.

Also, when you have received a newsletter you wish to stop, click on the "reply" button in your mail program, then type in the word "UNSUBSCRIBE" in the "Subject" field and send. WebMD Customer Service will unsubscribe you from that newsletter in two to three business days.

**ARTICLE 6**

**Updating Your Personal Information and Contacting WebMD**

You can always contact us in order to (1) delete your Personal Information from our systems if you terminate your membership in WebMD, (2) update the Personal Information that you have provided to us, and (3) change your preferences with respect to marketing contacts or other activities, by emailing us at [ support@webmd.net](mailto:support@webmd.net) _._ Such changes will not have any effect on other information that WebMD maintains. You may not delete your Personal Information if you wish to continue access to the Site and/or our Subscription Services.

It is not technologically possible to remove each and every record of the information you have provided to WebMD from our servers, even if you terminate your WebMD membership. The need to back-up our systems to protect information from inadvertent loss means that a copy of your Personal Information may exist in a non-erasable form that will be difficult or impossible for us to locate. Nevertheless, we promise that upon receiving your request, all Personal Information stored in the databases we actively use for research and daily business activities, and other readily searchable media, will be deleted.

Privacy as it applies to the Internet is a dynamic, rapidly developing area. In the future, we may make significant changes to our privacy policy affecting the use of the Personal Information we collect. We will notify you by email of any significant changes and obtain your "opt-in" consent to any significant new uses of your Personal Information, if it was collected from you prior to a significant change in this policy. We may also make non-significant changes to our Privacy Policy that generally will not affect our use of your Personal Information. You should also check this posted Privacy Policy for any future changes. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy or any revised policy, please exit the site immediately and terminate your membership in WebMD.

Revised April 6, 2001  
Copyright © 2001 WebMD Corporation. All rights reserved.
